

CREATIVE TECHNOLOGIST & FULL-STACK JS ENGINEER

- <u>+506 6240-2974</u> (Phone Number)
- josegomezdev.medium.com (Medium Blog)
- josegomez.dev@gmail.com (Email Address)
- in <u>josealejandrogomezcastro</u> (LinkedIn Profile)
- josegomez-dev (Github Profile)

ABOUT ME

I'm an innovative Software Engineer, with more than 5 years of experience in the full software development life-cycle.

Excellent troubleshooting and great teamwork skills.

Fan of Github Copilot and Chat GPT utilities to boost work stuff.

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

Cenfotec University

Advanced Technician in Software Engineering.

2015 - 2018

Informal Education

Learning Platforms: Team Treehouse | Egghead.io

2016 - Currently

Scrum Master Professional Certificate (Certiprof) | SMPC®

We develop knowledge to enable greater agility, processes optimization for software management and also improve progress visibility.

Nov 2019 (1 Month)

EXPERTISE

- Full Stack Development (MERN Stack)
 - Mongo.DB, Express.JS, React, Node.JS
- Frontend Development (Web Frameworks)
 - Angular, React (Next.JS), JS, Es6, Typescript
- Backend Development (Databases)
 - Mongo.DB (using Swagger Docs), Firebase

EXPERIENCE

Senior Product Developer

2022 - Jun 2023

Club Golf App by Foundation Lab LLC

We are a dynamic, forward-thinking startup with a highly agile, fully remote team. Our small but talented group leverages the latest cutting-edge technologies to build a sports betting mobile application, driving innovation and delivering exceptional solutions. (I was working as a Frontend engineer).

• Exp: React Native, TypeScript, React Hooks, Expo, Firebase.

Full-stack JS Engineer

Feb 2017 - 2022

Foundation Lab LLC

We build software solutions in Legal-Tech for Web and Mobile. I was working as a Full-stack Software Engineer involved in the full software development life-cycle.

We form an agile work team, with a great attitude towards changes and enthusiasm for new challenges.

- Exp: using third-party APIs (Stripe, PubNub, Google), and Codeship for CI/CD, Heroku as a Cloud Application Platform.
- Exp: React, Es6, NodeJS, MongoDB, Express, Mongoose.

App Developer

Aug 2016 - Mar 2018

Yes Duet (Co-Founder)

We created web single landing pages using HTML5, JS, PHP, and mobile applications using Ionic (Cross-Platform App Development)

- Business Strategist / Data Analyst
- Junior Frontend Developer.
- Exp: Ionic, AngularJS, JavaScript, SQL, Git.

ACTIVITY (LAST PROJECTS)

MUSICAL PATH | Jan 2024

We created our own innovate highly educational Unity Board-Game to learn musical grades from scratch.

SAGALAB | Sep 2023

Innovative project for education, to make the learning experience easier, interactive, and immersive.

ACTIVITY (Volunteering)

SPACEAPPS in Sustainable Development | Oct 2018

IMAGINE | Texas Tech University - Arduino, Angular, NodeJS, REST API.

HWTHON in Science and Technology | Aug 2018

TEC | Tecnológico de Costa Rica Top Performer in Software Engineering - Arduino, NodeJS, React, Axios.

Workshop in Cenfo | Sep 2017

Cross-Platform Mobile App Development with Xamarin and Ionic Frameworks.

JOSE G.

CREATIVE TECHNOLOGIST & FULL-STACK JS ENGINEER



josegomez-dev.github.io/resume (Website) josegomezdev.medium.com (Medium Blog)

PROFILE EXTENSION

This description includes more details of my training and experience as a Software Engineer. Also includes a timeline through several projects that I've been part of and some extra details.

2015 2016 2017 2019 2021 2022 **FOUNDATION LAB** SMPC Catarsis Musical CENFOTEC **YES DUET CLUB** Musical Project UNIVERSITY **CERTIPROF** Co-Founder & Senior Product **Betting Mobile** APP Developer Professional (Patreon) BIOSOFT Developer Application Certificate (1 Year) (1 Year...) (2 Years) (5 Years)... 2023 2024

SAGALAB BIOSOFT (3 Months) MUSICAL PATH
Game Designer &
Musical
Productor
(3 Months)

TECHNOLOGIES



LENGUAGE PROFICIENCY

- Spanish (native)
- English (intermediate)

TRAVEL STATUS

• USA (active)
I need to renew passport

KNOWLEDGE



STRONG FUNDAMENTALS IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING:

- Acquired in-depth knowledge of software development life cycle (SDLC) methodologies including Agile and Waterfall.
- Mastered core programming concepts, data structures, and algorithms, enabling efficient problem-solving and software development.
- Studied and applied software architecture principles to design scalable and efficient systems. (Gained proficiency in common design patterns).